oh rats this one's locked too just give me a sec guys we've been walking for a while now
how's about we set up camp here and rest for a bit
letting your stomach do the talking classy
it wasn't me darn it it figures she's hungry we've been eating snacks all day and nothing else
i don't think it's a good idea to stop just yet though lios the only food we managed to find
today is about a bowl's worth of treasure insects i say we keep going and get to the fourth floor
well i hear you but the monsters are just going to get stronger from here on i think it's important
we stay well rested still you're right we need food or we won't have the energy to fight but to
have the energy to fight we need rest and now i'm confused oh it's open
looks like this used to be a dining hall i bet it was something to see back in the day
the only ones using this room now are the undead even the rats stay away good because i refuse to
eat rats i wish we'd get attacked by something other than some dumb ghost it'd be awesome if a
roast pig came charging in what are you talking about we should be so lucky
wait we are we got food right in front of us
it's the living picture
lions what are you thinking it almost sucked you in i know that was the plan and you ruined it
what look at all those fat juicy grapes she's got just so we're clear here your plan was to eat
the food in the painting that's right it's a good idea don't you think you know what it means to taste
the pie in the sky don't you yeah but i'm not after some imaginary pie i can't eat if these are living
paintings then the pies in them should be eatable okay but you could also get killed in there
my point is if i'm in the painting then i can fight for the food in the painting too
whatever give it a try then and if you die that's on you deal i'll tie this rope to you
give her a tug and we'll pull you back out now which painting ah this one looks like it'll work
there's food waiting on the table right do your thing painting
who are you crap i've been spotted your sword i've never seen armor like that
but you are palace guard aren't you uh here let's go there's no time to waste goodness
sake i never have enough help hurry now stop dawdling back there
my word what a clever looking boy we have true and did you notice he has your nose when
you grow up little one you shall become a great king king
freyna i'm so happy for you just stand there hurry up bring the rest uh i um could use i have it
that does it i lost my appetite
i'm so ready to go he wants out let's go
well
i was this close to eating something there but then the mood in the room killed my appetite
why is the mood a problem how do you expect a guy to eat if the vibe's weird
anyway look i know i can do this i just need to find the right setting
okay and what would that be i don't know like maybe something more casual casual
hey how about this one everyone looks like they're having fun there's even a naked guy dancing perfect here
i go
you drunken lutar you are in the presence of the prince
stop it get off the table already i didn't leave him be
today is my wedding day this man was just celebrating not being insolent
but prince delgol delgol the baby from the other painting go on then
that was close delgol father i am so proud of how fine a man you have become here's to you and the kingdom
oh wow
oh
father
guess i'll grab what i can and eat when i get back
sorry your highness
yes he needs a doctor go and find him that elf was in the other painting too
is he the court jester
check it out guys i brought a whole bunch of goodies back so let's get to where the hell is it
i guess the painting won't let me take food with me i'll have to eat what i can while i'm still inside it
that does it that does it i'm gonna taste painting food this time or else
oh
looks like a coronation ceremony so that prince inherited the crown
i shall pray for the eternal prosperity of the country and its people
delicious delicious delicious i thought it would taste like paint but this is a real feast
um
um can i have some more
that was great man i'm stuffed
okay time to head back
hey it's that same elf
what are you doing here outsider oh i remember you were there when the prince was born and his
wedding what do you want are you after the throne
i will burn your flesh to ash
too gross
what happened this time you get to eat
i was at a table with a huge feast in front of me i ate as much as i could and got up to leave
then someone noticed i didn't belong there and grabbed my collar
she was so pissed at me you did crush his party i was so scared
how could i be hungry again after eating all that food oh damn i had the best meal and none of it came
back with me see told you it was a dumb idea dummy thanks for wasting our time i mean maybe but
the food did taste good
i guess this is the kitchen there's water in the next room so this should be a good enough
place to set up camp we could have reached the fourth floor by now if you weren't goofing off in those
damn paintings
my guts telling me that's a mimic
that chest definitely wasn't there before
it's in a perfect spot to get attention not too hidden not too obvious
the kind of spot those bastards love to ambush you from
well guys how about we get some sleep here okay got it chill chuck sound good sure
better not tell them about the mimic i know why i was and senshi would want to eat it which means i'll
have to open the chest no thanks
mimics over the years those bastards caused me nothing but grief oh good it's not locked and there's no trap
i had to pick the lock on this one so it can't be a mimic
if i open it from here it can't grab me
it's on the trail
damn mimics
are you okay what you're all quiet something bothering you
me uh-uh
betty's tired i say we let the kids sleep and one of us can take his turn keeping watch
for the last time i'm not a kid how old are you then none of your business ah geez why are you
always so secretive you never told us your age or where you're from i like to keep my work and
personal life separate if that's what you want but one day you'll regret it whatever
my stomach's gone soft on me i used to be able to go two days without eating
i need more water hey clumsy head
i'm gonna go get some water
wait up i'll go with you nah i'll be all right okay but watch your back it's in the next room
a coin insect maybe there's a nest around here if i find a few more i'll have a meal
i'm not as hardcore as laos but coin insects are good they're copycats like those damn mimics just
cuter wait don't go in there the mimic's hiding
great i forgot the weight of this water skin made me heavier there should be a lever around here
and i can't reach it should i yell for help better not the sound might draw other monsters
putting everyone in danger no worries or so will notice i didn't come back and come looking what
am i seeing knowing her she went right back to sleep take a breath opening doors is my specialty
i can do this no sweat i need to find the mechanism to open the door i'll be fine if i stay away from the
mimic i don't hear any ticking noises behind the walls so there's no time limit
i can tell there's switches on the walls which probably make spears shoot up from the floor
if i push them in the wrong order i'm done for i bet the words on this plate are my key to getting out
of here if only i could read this ancient language marcel could but she ain't here
i feel like i've seen this kind of writing before never mind better go over what i know there's three
switches in the corners of the room why three and in what order do i have to push them
there's another switch on the wall by the mimic i'm gonna have to deal with that rotten thing after
all maybe there's a hint somewhere i should be so lucky if i hit the switches randomly i'll get skewered
i'm tiny so maybe i can avoid them nope too risky huh i have no idea what i'm supposed to do
i guess all i can do is wait till the others awake
succumb it's all right
Two close calls. Get any closer.
Damn, these things are tough!
When you flip a mimic over, the way it struggles is cute.
With its belly up, you can see if it's a boy or a girl.
I don't want to hear a stupid trivia before I die!
Besides, how can I flip it over? There's no way!
Here goes nothing!
Damn, mimic. Hopefully the others heard me and...
Huh? You are empty this whole time, you son of a...
Wait, these letters...
They're the same ones as the one on the plate.
I know what these mean, so I can figure out...
Oh, crap!
The sun shall rise. The moon shall set.
The stars shall brightly shine.
Whoa!
Stop this, Nick!
And the winds of fortune shall blow your way forever!
Got it!
Come on! Chilchuk hasn't come back yet!
Chilchuk! He's dead. It's my fault.
Still alive, dummy.
Ooh, boy.
Chilchuk, you bagged a mimic. Nice going!
Thank you.
What a fine specimen it is.
I never cooked one of these before. Can't be too hard.
How do you even know it's safe to eat?
Don't you worry about that.
The book here says they aren't poisonous, but they may have poison in them depending on their diet.
So without its digestive tract, it'll be okay for us to eat.
There is nothing okay about anything you said.
Don't waste your breath, Marcel.
They're gonna cook it no matter what you say.
Let them. I don't care, cause there's no way I'm gonna eat it.
First we'll boil a big pot of water.
Then add some salt.
Stick the mimic in and pop the lid on.
Then wait.
It should be boiled enough.
It's ready.
It's so hard to get the meat out of it.
Try using the other end of that.
No good. Just push the meat in further.
Wait.
Chill Chuck, you mind if I borrow your thingies?
Thingies?
Those doohickeys you always use.
Your pickin' tools.
Pickin' tools.
Are you crazy?
No!
Don't worry.
Your quick boil should sterilize them.
I'm not worried about that!
No! Don't!
That's easy.
Here.
It's really good.
Yeah, this mimic sure is delicious.
I wonder how the meat from the body and the leg taste together.
Pretty dang awful.
Yeah, I heard the crustacean's mid-gut was icky.
If you knew the mimic was in there, why didn't you tell us?
I've had nothing but bad experiences with him.
The last thing I wanted to do was have to deal with another one.
Anyway, I made a lot of bad decisions.
At first, I was panicking because I thought it would eat the treasure insect.
But mimics don't eat treasure insects.
Huh?
Yeah, treasure insects eat mimics.
But when it finds a mimic, it crawls through an opening in the chest and lays its eggs.
Then when the eggs hatch, the larvae eat the mimic.
When they're mature, they look like treasure.
Someone comes along, picks them up, and boom.
They're free to find more mimics.
I hate that you know that.
And stop coddling me! I'm not a kid!
Tell me how old you are and I'll never do it again.
What happened to you today happened because you insist on being secretive.
So come on now and tell me how old you are.
Fine.
Ah!
I'm turning 29 this year.
Ah, you're just a kid after all.
I knew it.
I thought you were way older than that.
Okay then, how old are you guys?
Everyone's a kid to you races with long lives.
What's your problem?
Should I call you sir?
No! Just call me by my name!
Today's meal was another monster.
But tomorrow, they might be the meal.
Ah, dungeon food.
Delicious, in dungeon.
Ah!
What a month!
...